in this video we're going to look at how
to enter in receivables invoices and
credit memos in Dynamics GP and compare
that to the experience of entering those
documents in Dynamics 365 business
Central in my GP system I'm going to
enter an invoice for a computer repair
service we provided one of our customers
I'll begin by going to my receivables
transaction entry window and selecting
the customer we provided the service for
once I select the customer I can enter
in the amount for the service provided
and then post the
invoice let's say some time has passed
and the customer is asking for a credit
as a service isn't what they expected
next I'll go ahead and enter in a credit
memo and apply it to that original
invoice I can again select my customer
information and then enter in the credit
that they are asking
for I can also enter the description if
I want to provide more context of why
we're giving a credit to the
customer when I click on the apply
button I can get to the apply sales
document window where I can see my
outstanding invoices and look for the
original invoice that I had entered in
and select it and then click
okay and now I can post my credit memo
that has been applied to the
invoice now let's look at how we can
enter in receivables invoices and credit
memos in business Central
to create receivables invoices in
business Central I'll navigate to my
sales
journals in my sales Journal window I
can see I've created several different
batches and one for my sales in service
invoices with a default sales account
already selected if I drill into my
batch I can start entering information
for my invoice I'll first select the
document type of invoice and then change
the account type to customer
customer once I enter in the customer I
can then enter in a description of the
invoice similar to how I can do it in
GP finally I can enter in my document
amount for the service
provided if I want to look at the
posting accounts before posting I can go
into the GL entry and see the accounts
receivable and sales accounts that are
going to be posted to since that all
looks okay I'm going to go ahead and
post my
invoice next let's see how we can enter
in credit memos in business Central I'll
navigate back out to my batch and select
the credit memo batch where I've got a
different number series allowing me to
easily distinguish credit memos from
invoices in my credit memo batch again
I'll look at my document types and
select credit memo and then change the
account type to customer
next I'll select my customer and then
enter in the credit amount now we want
to apply this credit memo to the invoice
under processes I can pick apply entry
now I can see all the outstanding
invoices for my customer and scroll over
to see the computer repair invoice we
previously entered I'll go ahead and
select that and then process to apply
the credit memo to the
invoice now that I've got the credit
mimal apply to the invoice I'll go ahead
and post the
document in addition to sales journals
sales invoices can also be used to track
sales of services and items in
inventory to create a sales invoice
we'll click on the search icon and type
in sales
invoices once the list is returned I can
select sales invoices to get the sales
invoice list to
open now I'm going to click new to
create that new invoice
document from the customer name list I
can find the customer I need to enter in
my invoice
for down in the line section is where I
can switch the type to general ledger
account by selecting GL account then I
can select the sales account I want to
post the invoice
to and here I can search for that Sales
and Service revenue account select it
and then enter in the amount for the
invoice because the sales invoice allows
for additional flexibility it can also
include items that I track in inventory
on this document perhaps a customer also
purchased a desk from us I can capture
that information on the same transaction
and send the customer a single invoice
for both services and items
sold your receivables transactions can
be entered in business Central through
the use of sales journals and sales
invoices both providing function and
flexibility